Guide to the Henry Foner Papers and Photographs TAM.254
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Writings and Writings by Others, 70.2 Megabytes in 16 files
  - Conversations with my Father, by Herb Gardner, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 22a)
  - The Taft-Hartley Non-Communist Affidavit Trial of Ben Gold, by Craig Buckser, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Writings by Joseph Dorinson, 1997-2001 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Articles by Various Authors, Undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Article on the Teachers Union by Paul Becker and Martha Kransdorf, Undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Series IV: Subject Files
  Subseries A and B are arranged alphabetically; Subseries C is arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries A: General
    - 8th Annual Canadian Convention of International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 88th Infantry Division Association, 1969-2004 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 100 Great Black Americans, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Academic Freedom Center, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Ackley, John K. - Memorial and Related Materials, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Adler, Irving, 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Adler, Irving, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Animal Rights Materials, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Arbitration: Eberle Tanning Company and Fur, Leather and Machine Workers Union Joint Board (1 of 3), 1983 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Arbitration: Eberle Tanning Company and Fur, Leather and Machine Workers Union Joint Board (2 of 3), 1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Arbitration: Eberle Tanning Company and Fur, Leather and Machine Workers Union Joint Board (3 of 3), 1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Baron, Ben, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Bernhardt, Debra, 1998, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Bernhardt, Debra Memorial and Cesar Chavez Stamp Dedication, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Broadside, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Brooklyn: General, 1936-2001 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Brooklyn Baseball Cantata, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Brooklyn College Institute for Retired Professionals and Executives Course, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Brooklyn College Institute for Retired Professionals and Executives Course, 1999-2004 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Brooklyn Labor Movement, 1830-1839, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Burt, Sam, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Cammer, Harold Memorial and Writings, Undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Catskills Conference, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Catskills Conferences, 1997, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Catskills Conference, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Catskills Conferences, 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Center for Worker Education, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - City College Alumnus, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Community Control, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Dratch, Howard, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Eisenhower World Affairs Institute, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Elkland Leather Material, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Ewen Academic Freedom Center- Queens College, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Flatbush-Midwood Committee to Stop Nuclear Arms Proliferation (SNAP), Newsletters, 1993-2001 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Fur, Leather and Machine Workers Union, Local 174, Staff Benefits, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Fur Design Program, Fashion Institute of Technology, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Furriers Joint Council Trial, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Gollobin, Ira: 90th Birthday, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Griesi, James, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Gropper, William, Undated, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Grossman, Mildred, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Grove Press Organizing Campaign, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Guinier, Ewart - Memorial, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Herbst, Frank - Memorial and Other Information, 1979, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Horne, Lena - "From Me To You" (People's Voice column), 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - International Labor Press Association, 1972-1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Jeffries, Leonard, 1992-1994 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Jews and Blacks, 1948-1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Jews for Racial and Economic Justice Event, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Joint Board of Fur, Leather and Machine Workers Union Records (Cornell), Undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Kelber, Harry, 1989-1993 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Kelber, Harry - Songs and Music, Undated, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Kent, Rockwell, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Kimmelman, Edythe, Material, Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - King, Coretta Scott - Correspondence with, 1969, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Kings Highway Jewish Community School, 1960-1969 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Labor and Management Improper Practice, 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Labor Arts Website, 1997-2000 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Labor Arts Website, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Labor History - Philip Foner, Undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Labor Press Council, Undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Labor Resolutions on Trapping, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Labor Voices/Labor Tech: Conference, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Leather Workers of Fulton County: A History of Struggle, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Maathai, Wangari (International Women of Hope) - Signed Poster, 1998 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS002, Folder 1)
    - Mills, Saul - Greater New York CIO Council, 1940-1949 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Mills, Saul - Newspaper Clippings, 1941-1947 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Mills, Saul - Memorial, 1990-1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Millstone, Harry - Pillar of Labor, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Foner Documents, Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - National Association for the Visually Handicapped, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - National Health Insurance, 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Neighbor, Kew Gardens Hills Tenants Council, 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - New York City Labor Chorus, 1990-1999 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Ost, Milton, Memorial, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Peekskill 1999 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - People's Voice (Baseball), 1945-1987 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Plan-ette, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Political Material, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Polyp Prevention Trials, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Rappaport, Irving - Memorial, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Robbins, I. D., 1989-1996 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Robinson, Jackie: Conference, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Roots of Unity, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Rosenberg Commemoration, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Rubin, Ruth, 1953-1990 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Sacco and Vanzetti, 1920-1950 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Schappes, Morris and Sam Wallach Material, 1936-1989 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Schappes, Morris U. - Biographical Material, 1947-1997 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Out of the Shadows: The Political Writings of Eslanda Goode Robeson (presentation), 1998 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Smollett, Peter - Labor Film Guides/Essays, Letters, 1979-1996 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - SNAP Essay Contest, 1994-1997 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - SNAP 2001 Peace Essay Contest (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Song Collections, 1945-1965 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Straus, Dr. Mark, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Student Advocate, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Student Caravans for America, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Teachers Committee in Support of Dreamers and Fighters, 1994-1996 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Teachers Union Mailing Lists, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Teachers Union Materials, 1949-1997 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Teachers' Voluntary Service Association, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Teich, Victor: 80th Birthday, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Thursdays 'till 9: Newspaper articles, Reviews, Programs, Financial Information, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Ticker (CCNY School of Business), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Ullman, Sophie Louise, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1986-2003 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Voice of the Blue Devils, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Wagner, the Nazis, and Animal Rights (article), 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Wallach, Sam, Scholarship, 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - War Vignettes by Sol Rubin, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Weinstock, Harry, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Wildlife Legislation/Conservation Fund of America, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - William L. Patterson Foundation, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Woolis, Bernard: Leaflets, Undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Woolis Memorial, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Subseries B: Rapp-Coudert Committee
    - Academic Freedom "The Case of the NYU Seven", 1991, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Academic Freedom Writings, Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - American Student Movement, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence- ACLU and Rapp-Coudert Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence- Rapp Investigator Reports- Peace Movement, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Erasmus High School, Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Grebanier's Private Testimony, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Grover Cleveland High School, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - List of Names, Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Memorandum for the Members of Joint Legislative Committee to Investigate the Educational System of NYC, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1940-1981, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Rapp-Coudert Correspondence, 1940-2000 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Rapp-Coudert - Henry and Moe Foner, 1941, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Rapp-Coudert - Jack and Phil Foner, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Rapp-Coudert Committee: Profiles of Those Being Interviewed, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Rapp-Coudert Reunion, Songs and Correspondence, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Rapp-Coudert Victims, 1995, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Schappes vs. Board of Education, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - State of New York- Rapp-Coudert, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - State of New York- Rapp-Coudert (1of 2), 1940-1942 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - State of New York- Rapp-Coudert (2 of 2), 1940-1942 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Summary of Evidence against Individuals (1 of 2), Undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Summary of Evidence against Individuals (2 of 2), Undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Teachers Union, 1937-1941 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Subseries C: Paul Robeson
    - Robeson, Paul - Conferences, Undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Robeson, Paul - Book, Undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Robeson, Paul - "Plain Talk", 1940-1949 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Robeson, Paul - Study Guide, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Freedomways Salute to Paul Robeson, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Robeson, Paul - 75th Birthday, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Robeson, Paul - Miscellaneous Material, 1980-1999 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Robeson, Paul - Study Guide Correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Robeson, Paul - Chicago History 1921-1958, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Robeson, Paul - Centennial Celebration Gala Program, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - 100th Birthday Celebration Study Guide, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Robeson, Paul, Foundation, 1998-2000 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Robeson, Paul, Living Legacy, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Foundation Contributions, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Peekskill High School Celebration, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Robeson, Paul: Voice For the Millennium, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Bay Area Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Robeson, Paul, Foundation, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Robeson, Paul, Foundation, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Robeson, Paul: Postage Stamp, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 44)
- Series V: Addendum
  This unprocessed addendum includes correspondence, writings, and subject files, with the latter principally containing printed ephemera, including files on Paul Robeson, Labor Arts, and the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Veterans. This series also contains a box of plaques awarded to Foner.
  - Unprocessed Material (Box 11)
  - Unprocessed Material (Box Shared Tamiment OS001, Folder 1)
  - Unprocessed Materials related to Academic Freedom, 1948-1994 (Box 12)
  - Plaques, 1962-2003 (Box 16)
  - Henry Foner Hand-Drawn Cartoons 60th Birthday Poster, Mar 11, 1979 (Flat-file-folder 3 Right)
  - Unprocessed Graphics (Flat-file-folder 4)
- Series VI: Photographs
  The Henry Foner photographs span his entire life, documenting his childhood, family, activism, military service, birthdays, and speaking engagements. The Furriers and Leather Workers Union photographs include images of gatherings and activities and photographs of prominent policial figures (such as Fiorelle LaGuardia and W.E.B. DuBois). Also includes photographs from Foner's book For Better or Verse: Poems and Songs from 1938 to 2000.
  - Henry Foner (Box 13, Box 15)
  - International Fur and Leather Workers Union (Box 14)